APOORVA BHARDWAJ





Mob No: (+91) 8860634816 Email Id: apoorvabhardwajg@gmail.com

Key Highlights

Having 28 months of extensive experience as AWS & ETL Developer in Accenture. As AWS Developer worked on various virtual machines and cloud services. Automation of build and deployment of cloud applications. Experience in Data Warehouse, Big Data and end to end AWS application development projects using agile methodology.

Skills

AWS: Lambda, RedShift, S3, Athena, EC2, Glue, CloudWatch

Programming: Python, C++ ETL Tools: Talend, Ab Initio

RDBMS: SQL Server, Oracle, Teradata

Big Data Analytics: Hadoop, Hive, Pig, Sqoop

OS: Windows (7 & above), Unix/Linux

Shell Scripting: Bash

Microsoft Technologies: MS Excel, MS Word, MS PowerPoint,

MS Access

Utilities: SNOW, Jira, Confluence, ARD, ALM, Git Hub

Education

Guru Tegh Bahadur Institute of Technology, Delhi (2014-18)
B.Tech in Electronics & Communications Engineering (ECE)

80.81%

D.L.D.A.V. MODEL SCHOOL, Pitam Pura (2012-2014)

Scored 91.5 % (12th) Scored 10 C.G.P.A. (10th)

Certifications

- AWS Cloud Developer Associate
- Talend Data Integration Developer Practitioner
- Banking Foundation Learning

ACCENTURE

Work Experience

ASSOCIATE APPLICATION DEVELOPER

JAN 2020 - Current

U.S. Based Bank N.A.

Technologies Used: AWS, Talend, IBM BigInsights, HDFS (Hive & Pig), SQL, Unix, Autosys & SNOW

- Analyzed, developed, and implemented personalized client solutions using AWS platforms like Athena, Glue and Redshift.
- Developed Unix scripts from scratch for creating folders in S3 and performed file lifecycle management.
- Good knowledge in triggering event-driven and scheduled AWS lambda functions.
- Under the application FDIC (Federal Deposits Insurance corporation) created highly complex data transformation queries for different banking systems like IM (Impacs), ST (Savings Time), CAX(Citizens' Access) etc. using Hive and Pig.
- Managed end to end pipeline including data ingestion process from Datalake based on top of amazon S3 and other external storages like MySQL, flat and Mainframe file systems into Hadoop cluster and hive data warehouse.
- Created Unix wrappers (FDIC Generic Wrapper & FDIC Hive Wrapper) for executing hive code HDFS cluster by passing data migration specific parameters.
- Actively interacting with the client in the daily scrum calls to gather the business requirements and propose business solutions.

MAY 2019 - DEC 2019

U.S. Based Banking Group.

Technologies Used: Ab Initio, Oracle, SQL, Unix, Tableau

- Automated 2 different processes for Retail Services (Credit Initiation) and EDW (Enterprise Data Warehouse) cloud-based applications using Shell scripting to detect whether a sandbox has been migrated in the default directory or not.
- ETL testing from source to target for Ab Initio graph and Tableau UI Dashboard validations using Teradata. Worked in creation of data lake using AWS RedShift, Glue and S3. For downstream extract job used Talend.